Hello, my name is Mark Shuttleworth and I am delighted to welcome you to UbuCon Asia.
안녕하세요, 제 이름은 Mark Shuttleworth이며 UbuCon Asia에 오신 것을 환영합니다.
Now one of the big dreams of Open Source is that it would level the playing field that entrepreneurs,
오픈 소스의 큰 꿈 중 하나는 기업가, 혁신가 및 일반 사람들이 어느 나라에 있든,
innovators, and everyday people whichever no matter what country they are in, no matter
개인적인 상황이 무엇이든 관계없이
what their personal circumstances, all have access equally to the greatest technology that humanity can create.
모두가 인류가 만들 수 있는 최고의 기술에 동등하게 액세스할 수 있는 경쟁의 장을 평등하게 만드는 것입니다.
And we have seen over the last few decades Open Source become a tremendous leveler.
그리고 우리는 지난 수십 년 동안 오픈 소스가 모든 사람에게 평등한 기회를 주는 것을 보아왔습니다.
You don't have to be in Silicon Valley to create the next great startup. You don't have to be
차세대 스타트업을 만들기 위해 실리콘 밸리에 있지 않아도 됩니다.
wealthy to get access to sophisticated software to invent the future or just to participate
미래를 발명하거나 디지털 문화에 참여를 위한 정교한 소프트웨어에 액세스하기 위해 부유해 질 필요도 없습니다.
in digital culture. So it's an incredible privilege for those of us who work in Open Source
따라서 오픈 소스에서 일하는 우리 중 자신과 주변 사람들을 위해
to know that all around the world, people just like you are able to enjoy Open Source,
전 세계에서 여러분과 같은 사람들이 오픈 소스를 즐기고, 오픈 소스를 높이 평가 하며,
appreciate Open Source, and contribute to Open Source and use Open Source
오픈 소스에 기여하고, 오픈 소스를 사용하여 훌륭한 것을 구축
to build great things for themselves and for the people around them. Open Source is a great leveler
할 수 있다는 것을 안다는 것은 엄청난 특권입니다. 오픈 소스는 평등한 기회를 훌륭하게 가져다 주며
and it touches every industry. Just in our own work at Canonical we work with telecommunications
이는 모든 산업에 영향을 미칩니다 . Canonical에서 통신사와 함께 하는 일만 보아도,
companies, telcos changing the nature of bandwidth to the home, bandwidth to businesses,
통신사는 가정에 대한 대역폭, 비즈니스에 대한 대역폭, 통신 서비스의 특성을 변화 시킵니다.
Open Source in factories, there's Open Source in the robots that make the cars, there's Open Source
공장에 오픈 소스가 있고, 자동차를 만드는 로봇에 오픈 소스가 있고,
in the clouds that have all the data that make cars autonomous, there's Open Source in the high
자동차를 자율적으로 만드는 모든 데이터가 있는 클라우드에 오픈 소스가 있고,
performance computing that essentially simulates cars to make them safer. Open Source is changing
자동차를 더 안전하게 만들기 위해 기본적으로 시뮬레이션하는 고성능 컴퓨팅에도 오픈소스가 있습니다.
every industry from finance to smart cities to smart homes. I hope that the UbuCon Asia agenda
오픈소스는 금융에서 스마트 시티, 스마트 홈에 이르기까지 모든 산업을 변화시키고 있습니다.
technology future. I hope that Open Source will be at the heart of it, and that this conference
오픈 소스로 가는 관문이 되기를 바랍니다 . 오픈소스가 그 중심에 있고, 그리고 이 컨퍼런스가
can be a meaningful step for you to that future. I want to thank the organizers. It takes an enormous
그 미래를 향한 의미 있는 발걸음이 되기를 바랍니다. 주최측에 감사 인사를 전하고 싶습니다.
amount of work to pull together different people, pull together program, get people
서로 다른 사람들을 한데 모으고, 프로그램을 만들고,
prepared to speak, and then to make everybody aware of it. I hope you have a great time. Thank
사람들이 발표 준비를 하게 하고, 모든 사람이 그것을 알도록 알리려면 엄청난 양의 작업이 필요 합니다. 좋은 시간 가지셨으면 좋겠습니다.
you for your interest in Ubuntu. Thank you to those of you who are members of the community
우분투에 관심을 가져주셔서 감사합니다. 커뮤니티의 구성원이자 우분투 기여자이신 여러분들께 감사 드립니다.
and contributors to Ubuntu. It is your work that makes Ubuntu great. Have a great conference.
여러분들의 작업이 우분투를 더 훌륭하게 만듭니다. 즐거운 컨퍼런스 되시기 바랍니다.